<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database on Thomas Chester&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://tjchester.github.io/tags/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Database on Thomas Chester&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tjchester.github.io/tags/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Test Data for Rails Projects</title>
      <link>http://tjchester.github.io/post/2016-03-17-generating-test-data-for-rails-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tjchester.github.io/post/2016-03-17-generating-test-data-for-rails-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How often have you created a database for a new Rails application and then sat staring at the empty tables? Often times when building a new application you need sample data to help flesh out the user interface or to show off the application to your customer. Rails provides a convenient method of loading this data via the &lt;em&gt;seeds.rb&lt;/em&gt; file, but you still have to create the content for this file. This article will discuss a mostly automated way of generating content for your database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is A Database?</title>
      <link>http://tjchester.github.io/post/2016-03-03-what-is-a-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tjchester.github.io/post/2016-03-03-what-is-a-database/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I were to say the word &lt;em&gt;database&lt;/em&gt; to you, what might be the first thing that would come to mind. It would probably depend on your current situation and background. Corporate developers might immediately think of Oracle Database or Microsoft SQL Server. Open-source developers would probably think of MySQL/MariaDB, PostgreSQL, or MongoDB. Desktop users might think of Microsoft Access, Paradox, or even dBase. In general, what you are actually thinking of is the DBMS (Database Management System) or the software that allows you to interact with the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>